Previously on Transformers: Prime
在上一集里
With the power of the Matrix no longer within him...
由于领导模块的力量不再护佑他
It would stand to reason that Optimus has reverted to his pre-Prime state.
理所当然的 他回到了成为领袖之前的状态：
A high-frequency signal...
一个高频信号…
With an embedded message.
内含一个加密的信息
Where is Optimus?
擎天柱在哪儿？
Unless you know where Megatron is hiding his Space-bridge...
除非你知道威震天把他的太空桥藏在何处…
Space... bridge!
太空…桥！
... They actually finished building it without my supervision?!
…他们在没有我指导的情况下完成了？！
Once we secure the Space-bridge we'll send for Jack.
一旦我们控制了太空桥 就叫杰克过来
You three need to hold it long enough for Jack and me
你们三个还要撑足够长的时间
to get to Cybertron and back.
直到我和杰克从塞博特恩回来
How could I possibly be "Optimus Prime"?
我怎么可能是擎天柱？
Vector Sigma's true location is shrouded in myth and rumor, Jack.
魔力神球的真实位置早就被神话跟谣传歪曲了 杰克
It is said the path of the Primes' leads there.
传说领袖之路会通向那里
We must be close.
我们肯定很接近了
Vector Sigma is... down here?
魔力神球…在下面？
Kaon didn't always belong to the Decepticons.
卡隆也不是一直都属于霸天虎
Megatron took it as a capital.
威震天把它当做首都
Apparently without ever realising what lay beneath their feet.
显然他们没发现脚下藏着什么
Arcee!
阿尔茜！
We are being attacked by some kind of...
我们正遭到某种…
giant bot-beetle!
…巨型甲虫的攻击！
An Insecticon!
一个机器昆虫！
A what?
一个什么？
What are Decepticons doing on Cybertron?
霸天虎在塞博特恩做什么？
A few remained in stasis.
有几个留下来的 休眠在此
Sentries, should the enemy return.
是看家的 以防止敌人突然造访
Jack! Go!
杰克！走！
Seriously?
你当真吗？
Without Arcee? She's his guide!
离开阿尔茜？她是他的向导！
No, nurse Darby, Arcee is Jack's backup.
不 达比护士 阿尔茜是杰克的后援
The Key-Card is his guide.
钥匙芯片才是他的向导
Do it!
快走啊！
Listen to her, Jack.
听她的 杰克
You've made it this far. Optimus is counting on you.
你已经走到这一步了 擎天柱还指望着你呢
Roger that, Mom.
明白 妈妈
Orion!
奥利安！
Have you made progess with project "Iacon"?
你的“铁堡”计划有进展吗？
It seems I am a bit rustier than I thought.
看起来我比想象的还要笨
Might that have anything to do with the nature of your after-hours research?
那是否和你喜欢做课外研究的天性有关？
Did I fail to mention that we would be tracking your activities?
我是不是没提过我们会追踪你的动向？
Why does history portray me siding with the Autobot aggressors?
为什么历史描绘中我跟汽车人的匪首是同一阵营？
And why did Starscream call me a Prime?
还有红蜘蛛为什么称我为领袖？
I must know!
我必须知道！
Who am I?
我是谁？
You are my clerk.
你是我的手下
Now get back to work and decode that database.
现在回去工作然后把数据库破译出来
... No.
…不
I would rather erase my findings
我宁可把我的发现都删掉
Did you really think that we wouldn't be tracking and documenting every iota of your invaluable research?
你真的以为我们没有追踪和记录 你那些珍贵研究的点点滴滴吗？
One of our sentries was activated, on Cybertron?
我们留在塞博特恩的一个哨兵被激活了？
You told me our planet was dead.
你跟我说我们的星球已经死了
That is beside the point. Guards!
那不是重点 来人！
You will finish project "Iacon" by the time I return
在我回来之前你就得完成“铁堡”计划
or I will carve out your Spark before your very eyes!
否则我就让你亲眼看着我挖出你的火种！
The activity log indicates my Space-bridge was set for Cybertron...
活动记录显示我的太空桥定向到了塞博特恩…
... and remains open?
…而且一直开着？
The only possible reason the Autobots would take such a risk...
汽车人如此大胆的冒险只有一个原因
... would be to restore their precious Optimus Prime.
…为了让他们的宝贝擎天柱复原
Hey everyone! I'm in.
各位 我进来了！
Sweet!
太好了！
This is... Wow.
这就是…哇哦
Commencing download. ... I think.
开始下载了…我猜
Soon, Optimus.
就快了 擎天柱
No one told you to stop, Pax.
没人让你停下来 派克斯
I believe Megatron intends to use whatever he finds in project "Iacon" to harm the Autobots.
我相信威震天打算用“铁堡”计划的 成果来对付汽车人
Please. We can warn them.
求你们了 我们得警告他们
This is taking awhile.
这需要时间
Of course it is.
这是当然
We are talking about the collective wisdom of the Primes.
这可是历代领袖的智慧结晶
What is it, Jack?
怎么了 杰克？
Scraplets!
吸屑虫
What's a scraplet?
吸屑虫是什么？
Why did it have to be scraplets?!
为什么偏偏是吸屑虫！
If they chew through Vector Sigma before the Matrix fully reloads...
如果它们在领导模块完全重启之前咬穿魔力神球…
So Vector Sigma is more than legend.
那么说…魔力神球并不只是传说
You Autobots have gone to impressive lengths to recover your Leader.
你们汽车人拯救首领的举动真是令人印象深刻
Be assured, I shall never underestimate you again.
请相信…我决不会再低估你们了
Now... I assume the one called Arcee will be stepping through that portal with the reloaded Matrix of Leadership in hand.
现在… 我猜那个叫阿尔茜的 正拿着重启的领导模块从那个隧道中走过来
We hold the Space-bridge at all costs!
我们得不惜一切代价守住太空桥！
You're going down, Bucket-head!
给我滚下去 铁桶头！
Jack?
杰克？
Oh no-no-no-no, don't quit now!
哦 不 不 现在可别失灵！
Arcee?
阿尔茜？
Back off, bug!
给我退回去 虫子！
Hey, guys! The main course!
嘿 伙计们 主菜来了！
I have the Matrix.
领导模块搞定！
Let's roll.
我们快走
You have to admit,
你必须承认
it's a privilege to stomp the former leader of the Autobots.
践踏汽车人的前任领袖也让人倍感殊荣
No, please... stop.
别 请…住手
Enough!
够了！
I'm... armed?
我…有武器？
We're almost there.
我们就快到了
Ratchet, we have the Matrix.
救护车 我们搞定了领导模块
We're coming through.
我们正赶过来
Ratchet?
救护车？
Something's wrong.
有点不对劲
We can’t... not go through, can we?
我们无论如何也得过去 不是吗？
Come, Arcee.
来啊 阿尔茜
So that I might end the lineage of the Primes for all time.
来让我终结这领袖的传承
I cannot allow that to happen, Megatron.
我决不允许 威震天
And why should you care, Orion Pax?
你这是狗拿耗子 奥利安・派克斯
You are no Prime.
你又不是领袖
That may be true. Or yet another deception?
也许这是事实 也许又是另一个谎言？
But this much I do know:
不过有一点我很明白：
my sympathies lie with the Autobots and you are not one of us.
我对汽车人有认同感 而你不是我们当中的一员
Your Spark may be in the right place, Orion.
也许你的火种真的找准了位置 奥利安
But you have much to learn before you can hope to ever again stand your ground against me.
不过你要是想跟我过招 那还早着呢
A moment, sadly, which shall never come.
很遗憾 那一天不会来临的
Are you... certain I am worthy?
你…确定我配得上？
You have no idea.
你不了解自己的伟大
How nice of you to join our little reunion.
很高兴你能加入这温馨的大团圆
Now, if you please...
现在 你可否交出…
the Matrix?!
领导模块？！
Noo!
不！
Megatron...
威震天…
Be gone!
退下！
Ratchet! How did we arrive here?
救护车！我们怎么会来到这里？
Long story, old friend.
说来话长 老朋友
Base to Arcee!
基地呼叫阿尔茜！
We're reading five Autobot life signals down there.
我们检测到下面有五个汽车人的生命信号
Is Prime with you?
擎天柱跟你们在一起吗？
And Jack.
还有杰克
Yes!
好哎！
Ah!
啊！
It's ours!
是接我们的！
Autobots, fall back!
汽车人 返回基地！
This time he's coming with us.
这一次 他可不会跟你走了！
Jack!
杰克！
Optimus?
擎天柱？
Hello, Rafael.
你好 拉斐尔
- Woah. - The Big Guy remembers us! Woo-hoo!
- 哇！ - 老大记起咱们了！
Although it seems there is much I do not remember.
虽然好像有些事情我记不起来了
Optimus. It has truly been our darkest hour.
擎天柱 我们度过了最黑暗的时刻
But know this:
但同时
from every indication your Spark
种种迹象表明 你的火种
never ceased being that of an Autobot.
从未抛弃过汽车人的理想